



Personal Profile

I am a highly adaptable, goal-oriented professional with a valid Spanish work permit (NIE – Y0417755C). I worked as a Military Health Care Provider on an Army base in Germany for five years before teaching English as a TEFL certified English teacher (CVN-00167819 and certified young learners teacher CVN-820) in Spain for the last ten years. My formal education is focused on Religion and Philosophy, but I also study western history as a hobby and have a deep love of math and science from my studies to become a private pilot. I have a Spanish wife of fourteen years and two bilingual children, a twelve years old daughter and a ten year old son with whom I spend my free time.

Professional Experience

Private school Algebra Teacher

Sunrise Academy LLC - Orange City, Florida. September 2021 - May 2022

- Planned and organized classes to be taught throughout the week/month /year.
- Prepared quizzes and tests according the Florida state education standards.

TOFL English Teacher

American English Academy - Madrid, Spain. January 2009 - August 2012

English in Action – Alcorcon, Spain. September 2012 - August 2017

EGA Group English Academy - Alcorcon, Spain. September 2017 - June 2021

- Prepared and organized English classes for all age and grade levels.
- Adapted through the Covid-19 crisis during the implementation of online classes.

U.S. Army Pediatric/Dermatological Medical Assistant

United States Army – Heidelberg, Germany. September 2004 - January 2009

- Prepared and organized patients' appointments and records in a dermatological clinic.
- Prepared and assisted with dermatological operations with an Army doctor.

Head Gymnastics Teacher

A Class Apart Dance Academy – Deltona, Florida. September 2002 - June 2004

- Prepared and presented dynamic gymnastics classes to the academy's dancers.
- Organized end of year routines to demonstrate the skills learned during the year.

Sales Floor Associate

J.C. Penny Department Store – Sanford, Florida. January 2000 - September 2002

Store of Knowledge - Sanford, Florida, September 1999 - December 1999

- Interacted with clients to encourage product sale and satisfaction
- Took an active role in store area organization and daily bank roll processing



Formal Education

TEFL Teacher's Certification and Young Learners Certification

<u>The International TEFL Corporation</u> - September 2008-December 2008

Masters in Human Relations

The University of Oklahoma - Schwetzingen, Germany - September 2005 - September 2008

B.A. (Major in Religious Studies, Minor in Spanish and Philosophy)

Stetson University - July 1999 - August 2004

Universidad de Complutense de Madrid (study abroad program) - July 2002 - December 2002

Languages

English – Native level spoken, heard, written and read Spanish – C1 conversational level spoken, heard, written and read German – A2 Primer level spoken, heard, written and read French – A2 Primer level spoken, heard, written and read

Skills

- Motivated and solution focused
- Experience with computers and online classes
- Creative-minded and adventurous
- Experienced public speaker
- Well-travelled and understanding of intercultural relations
- Licensed Private pilot and open-water SCUBA diver
- Experience with a variety of healthcare and emergency medicine